

Gayan Rathnayaka

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

Senior developer with 6+ years of designing and developing scalable, high performing applications with a rich user experience. Well acquainted with agile practices. A friendly team player. Technology enthusiast who embraces challenges and keen in learning novel technologies.

gayansrathnayaka@outlook.com 📞+94712433694 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/gayanrathnayaka

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer IFS R&D 2021/08-present

https://www.linkedin.com/company/ifs

Colombo , Sri Lanka

Working as a senior developer in lifecycle experience team (ALE), which consists of 30 members grouped into 4 cross-functional sub-teams. ALE develops and maintains an application to automatically deploy IFS core product as customized environments to carry out customizations on top of the core product and to spin off demo environments from the core application easily.

- Analyzing requirements
- Designing and developing frontend components with a good user experience.
- ♦ Designing and developing scalable and maintainable API s.
- ⟨⟩ Writing unit tests.
- Conducting code reviews.
- Revamping and refactoring existing code for better maintenance and performance

Tech and Tools

- Angular
- .NET web API
- Azure Dev Ops
- Azure Storage
- Azure Blob
- Gitlab Pipelines

Senior Software Engineer

Zone 24 X 7

2020/04-2021/08

in https://www.linkedin.com/company/zone24x7/

Colombo, Sri Lanka

Worked as a senior developer/team lead frontend team in a cross functional team with 10 members. implemented a SaaS application to manage documents in any organizations with auditing capabilities as well.

- Analyzing requirements.
- Designing and developing frontend components with a good user experience.
- Designing and developing scalable and maintainable API s.
- Writing unit tests.
- Conducting code reviews.
- Conducting interviews.
- Mentoring junior team members.

- Tech and Tools
- React / React FC
- .NET web API
- Azure Functions
- Rabbit MQ
- MSSQL
- **Event Bus**
- Entity Framework

Senior Software Engineer Qualitapps Europe 2017/07-2020/04

in https://www.linkedin.com/company/qualitapps-europe-s.l/

Colombo , Sri Lanka

Worked as a senior developer/team lead in a cross functional team with 5 members. implemented a SaaS application from scratch to manage reservations for motels in South American region.

Worked as a senior developer in a cross functional team with 4 members. Worked in an application to manage leaves of healthcare industries in Spain.

- Analyzing requirements
- ♦ Designing and developing frontend components with a good user experience.
- ✓> Designing and developing scalable and maintainable API s.
- Directly managing with the client.
- Conducting code reviews.
- Conducting interviews.
- Mentoring junior team members.
- Bug fixes.

Tech and Tools

- Angular 6
- .NET web API
- Azure Functions
- Fabric JS
- MySql
- SignalR
- **Entity Framework**
- Hangfire
- Sync Fusion

Software Engineer Sampath Information Technologies 2015/04-2017/07 in https://www.linkedin.com/company/sampath-it/

O Colombo , Sri Lanka

Worked as a developer in a data processing application for a telco client in a team with 15 members. Worked with both web forms and windows forms to capture data from physical documents using image processing and process that data to generate real time dashboards.

- Analyzing requirements.
- Deliver well-structured and high-quality code.
- Bug fixes.

Tech and Tools

- ASP.NET MVC
- C# Forms
- Hangfire
- PostgreSQL

Academic Qualifications

Msc in Information Technology University Of Colombo 2015-2017

Bsc in Information Technology Sheffield Hallam University 2010 - 2014

- in https://www.linkedin.com/school/university-of-colombo/
- O Colombo , Sri Lanka
- in https://www.linkedin.com/school/sheffield-hallam-university/
- Sheffield , United Kingdom

Technical Skills

Programming languages

Javascript TypeScript C#

Frameworks and Libraries

ReactReduxAngular.NET Web APIRabbit MQASP.NET MVCSignalRHangfire

Databases

MSSQL MySQL PostgreSQL Azure Storage

Software Tools

Visual Studio Visual Studio Code Azure DevOps Azure Portal